Who else has something like this hanging
on their wall with a story that their
grandpa told them that's never been
written down? Today I'm here with Joe
and Whitney and we're going to be
touring Whitney's house. This house was
built in 1931. Who was it built by
again? Harvey P. Smith and Ferdinand
Reyberger, a stone mason. And we're
going to see all kinds of symbols all
around the house just like we did at the
hotel. This is the first Freemason
structure I've cognizantly been in and
as a lifelong builder, I cannot wait to
see. This is very impressive just from
the outside. Where do you want to start?
>> Let's go to the koi pond. Let's hit the
koi pond before the sun goes down.
How many acres is this property,
Whitney?
>> six acres.
Oh.
Interesting number. Have you seen any
symbols like these, Joe? Everything is a
symbol in my opinion.
>> These are called encaustic tiles. They
have mineral pigments and they go all
the way through. And the number of
everything is very pertinent to me. 1 2
3 4 5 6. When you deal with the
Freemasons, it's always a numbers game.
Like, [music] why did they put this
many? It'll make you feel a little
crazy. When we get done,
if you want to see my house, it's right
here behind us.
>> [laughter]
>> That's my house.
Parker.
Why does this duck remind me of you?
Because it's green. Green is my favorite
color.
>> [laughter]
>> This was all constructed originally?
Yeah. I put the crystals on top of this
bit.
The rest of it is more like the Spanish
revival.
>> Do you know the dimensions of this?
Because if I had to guess, I would say
that the outer perimeter matches the
inside perimeter just like the stuff in
the Egyptian tombs. I think it's a bit
more like a Solomon's Temple actually,
the whole property and there's a stable
in the back. It's almost like a
miniature or real fake in a way.
There's a reservoir across the street.
It used to supply the whole town with
water.
Um, notice uh the little channels. I
almost fell over this. This channel
right here fed the whole town water
basically. You can hear the water
flowing.
Now, 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13
If you know anything about the
Freemasons and the number 13 That's
significant. But this is a natural
aquifer? It used to all of this used to
be lined with iron ore rock like the
tomato builders put on and they
transported the water in an old Grecian
aqueduct kind of format throughout the
whole town so we could have spring fed
water originally here. Wow.
Yeah, of course the Freemasons came to
the water.
It was built by the CCC and WPA
programs. Okay.
>> Great Depression. Yeah, the New Deal.
The date on that bridge you look at the
top of it was 1916. And it's still
standing.
>> a name CR Kelly and he built he paved
the sidewalk for the hotel. He's
probably one of the builders that were
Famous, yeah. See, I wonder what kind of
pitch this is. I wonder if it might be
the same 22 and 1/2 from the Egyptian
pyramids. Exactly.
Am I right on that? Is it 22 and 1/2?
Um, here it is right here.
There it is.
And there's 31 of these all around the
whole property. It's past but yes, it
winds kind of like a snake. Or maybe
like the Milky Way. Here, what I think
is so cool is this curve. Like they're
really showing off with this wall. I'm
going to be honest, okay? So they cut
this whole thing out and then made this
rock wall. If you think about how it
rains in Texas
>> shape of pi. For real, it's a spiral. It
goes all the Oh, I'm sure everything is
perfectly laid out on a geometric
pattern of some kind that we're just too
dumb not to see.
>> [laughter]
>> I wonder how many countless laborers
worked on this stuff without knowing
what they were doing.
>> Well, that was the thing with becoming a
Freemason. This was a wonderful
accreditation that you could get if you
didn't have like
a college or you weren't going to higher
education. From the very beginning of
time if you worked on Solomon's Temple,
you got the accreditation of a Mason
using your hands and these certain
skilled, you know, things that they did.
And so that's how you became it. College
is nothing but information with no
application.
>> God with your hands, basically. So
Harvey B. Smith was toward all the
missions in the United States. Woah.
>> his job. He did that for President
[music] Roosevelt. And these he put all
of his favorite attributes into this one
home. [music] Now Parker, what do you
see I see you looking.
What are you picking up here? Now this
is I love how everything is half. What
do you think this is? It's totally Well,
we have
>> Have you seen this before anywhere in
your life?
>> No. No. And I'm always going, "Where's
the other half?"
>> oddly familiar.
>> And also like from what era? Do you know
what I mean? So I looked [music] this up
and I found some similar things. Chinese
temples, the Titanic. This absolutely
means transformation. [music]
There's so many things you can look at.
What is this? It looks so modern. Mhm.
Where's the I want to know where the
other half is. So we have the whole the
whole piece up there.
>> And so the other piece is up there?
Yeah, they're all in eight, nine, 10,
eight, nine, 10.
Hey Parker, you know what these also
remind me of? Huh?
The symbols on a wiring diagram.
Electrical symbols.
>> Schematic. Well, it's like a fabric and
you're you can you can't stand in one or
the other. It's kind of you have to work
to keep your feet within one. Do you
know what I mean?
Five and four. The numerology's already
boggling my mind. I'm not smart enough
for this. What what did you say? It's
just a creepy little tidbit about me. My
birthday's 10 [music] 13 75.
And so the Knights Templar, that's why
we have Friday the 13th. They went down
on on October The the Cathars. We hadn't
even made it inside.
>> [laughter]
>> Look at the shape on this door. I keep
looking at it.
I bet you it must have face and hair.
And then
do you see it's like a feminine shape.
This is a very masculine veil.
Masculine?
Feminine. And just like me and Alex, you
You to go through her to get to me.
>> [laughter]
>> I mean
Wow.
This is nice.
How can you count those Parker? How many
stairs do you have?
13 again.
Probably just a strange coincidence,
don't you think? No. What are these
glasses?
It's stained glass I believe. Yeah, and
all the missions was only one with
um stained glass. And so that's what was
cool that he made this wood stained
glass. This is fantastic.
Once again, two steps. You see the
stories on the stairs? I can see it. See
this right here look, it's just like the
door frames.
This right here. Five crosses there.
What do you think that one means?
No, see I don't think anything here was
done on accident. Cross symbol, circle
within a circle, everything is beveled
and curved. I mean look at the
fireplace.
Yeah, no nails. Oh, it's a Chinese
wedding bell.
It's all dowelled together.
Every bit of it.
I built some stuff with no nails in
Costa Rica off tension and friction man,
and it's not nearly as impressive as
this. This is all hand carved.
>> Mhm. Bro, imagine carving this out of a
solid piece of wood.
We think we got carpenters today. Now,
what do we have here? The garden. And
then
>> [music]
>> see you can see the stone path below.
Wow, the first square doors here. Brass
hinges. As a carpenter
>> [music]
>> I'm just sitting here going I would hate
to have to put in all these flat head
screws in solid hardwood doors.
And they weren't using power tools
really.
Oh, man.
But
I love it.
Pink and blue and love all over. Let me
guess, is there a razor throw away in
here?
Probably with the bath. You know how
many walls I tore out and there was a
pile of rusted razors in the back?
>> A lot. I absolutely love it. What was
this one again? The
spirit wall? Yeah.
And it's
it's a
psycher's Or what was the threshold?
Threshold. Psycher's, yes. You got to
explain this to me. This one right here
is kind of
They don't want me to do it. I don't
think it's bad at all.
I I just the eyes are It's a simple
transformation. It actually is. Now, if
you know anything about Abraham and
Isaac,
I just say the eyes. You know, if you
look at it, the eyes are the window to
the soul.
And this one is
>> This guy is it. He's not playing around
with us. Yeah.
I need a tape measure to know all the
dimensions of all of this.
I just and I want to pull the diagonals.
Everything is so perfectly lined up. Do
you think this room is a perfect square?
Cuz you know how usually houses aren't
square at all.
Oh, I bet you if you pull diagonals on
here, you're going to be winning a
close. Mhm. Made this back corner 5 6
panes, but I bet you some things might
not be square. They might be
parallelograms.
>> Yeah. To to signify distorted dimension.
You don't even have a perfect one. You
can bend one. This is what I love the
most.
The curvatures. Me, too.
That is so much work.
You know, if you doing block, you go up
there and square it off, no problem. Run
a trial down there and and make you a
good clean joint. But that, I think they
went to immense [music] trouble to
signify something. Right there in plain
sight for anybody who has eyes to see
and ears to hear. Is this kitchen? I
love the tile. Have you ever seen a tile
before? No. The smaller the grout line,
the harder it is.
>> Yes. And if you look at these corners,
Mhm. look at all their cuts. I mean,
pretty fantastical, if you ask me. Oh my
goodness.
1 2 3 4 5 [music] 6 7 8.
>> Mhm.
I bet you that corner is seven.
So, look, all the corners are are seven
and then everything else is eights.
I'm still looking for my six over five.
Woah. Yeah.
Same Celtic. Which Hey, now Parker, if
you look at this
So, you see a Celtic cross also kind of
looks like a winding, doesn't it?
See, a lot of these A lot of these
symbols look like electrical symbols to
me. This is like fire. And how many? 1 2
3 4 5 6 7.
And hey, baby, there's my I said I've
been looking for it. Six over five.
There's six, five. One fire.
Oh, lord almighty. Woah. Hey, I didn't
even notice this. Yeah. Check out the
double crosses.
Woah. And threes.
I'm telling you.
I I wouldn't sleep at Winken here. I'd
have an abacus and a slide rule.
This is fantastic. Now, that's the
world.
What is that? The two pillars, the sun,
the moon. This is what I don't get. You
see, you have the world, I guess that's
[music] going to be our world, and then
you have the spirit world, God at the
bottom, three stairs.
>> I see the one at the the bottom of the
pillars inside. Right here?
>> That's what I've been wondering. What's
going on there?
>> of looks like the same shape of the
swords.
>> [music]
>> It looks like this.
It does. You know what I'm getting at?
>> praying hands. You know what I'm hopeful
of, Parker?
I'm hopeful that people [music] online
see this and give us answers. Yeah. You
know, you can kind of scan the whole
world and see what other people know,
because who else has something like this
hanging on their wall with the story
that their grandpa told them that's
never been written down. There's a lot
of information that's never been written
down for obvious reasons, and it's
passed along [music] from trusted person
to trusted person. I'd say that that's
from the 1920s. Now, I don't have time
to count all these and all these little
rays. But man, This is probably from the
20s. This is fantastic.